星际之门亚特兰蒂斯  前情回顾
Previously on  stargate atlantis ...
你身上有幽灵的基因
You have some wraith dna.
我父亲和别人说这是天赋禀异
My father told people that it was a gift.
他们已经追踪到我的行迹
Ah, they've picked up my signal.
一种外太空跟踪器
A subspace tracking device.
我已植入这个
I had it implanted.
蜂巢战舰正在互相攻击
The hives are firing on each other.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
100%确定
Definitely.
他们还是以命相搏
They're not pulling any punches either.
直到我的飞船壮烈牺牲了
So all it took was the destruction of my ship
你才肯相信我啊
For you to finally trust me.
不  我仍然不相信你
Oh, not true, I still don't trust you.
我已改良了这种逆转录酶
I've refined the retrovirus
创造了完美的平衡
To create the perfect balance--
可以超越人类极限
Ability well beyond any normal human,
除了一个弱点外
But without the one weakness
幽灵组将永不衰败
That will be the downfall of the wraith...
那就是我们须要进食
The need to feed.
我仍觉得我们要带点后援部队
I still say we should'v e brought backup.
小飞船或者海军陆战队之类的
Another jumper, or a marine unit, Something.
罗德尼  这是
This is intended to be
一次外交任务
A diplomatic mission, rodney.
你带这么多人想传达什么信息?
What kind of message would that send?
希望是强势信息
Well, a strong one, hopefully.
如果他们不惊慌
Everybody's going to be fine
那么我们就会没事
If they don't panic.
你说的容易
Easier said than done.
我们到了
There they are.
天啊  这飞船好巨大啊
My god, how big is that thing?
从没在太空看过蜂巢战舰?
Never seen a hive in space, huh?
从没看到过
I've never seen one period.
我是说在影像记录中见过  但没亲眼看到
I mean, I've seen video logs, but never in person.
你一定会深刻记住这个第一次的
Well, you never forget your first.
他们知道我们来了
They know we're here.
明显是的
Apparently.
我们接受到一个信号
We're receiving a transmission.
靠边停船
Docking instructions.
你以为是什么  "你好  客人辛苦了"
What, no, "hello. greetings, weary travelers?"
我猜也不是
Guess not.
看来不会有红地毯来迎接我们了
So much for the red carpet.
接下来怎么办
So, what happens now?
根据历史经验
Well, if history has taught us anything,
我们会被出卖
This is the part where we get double-crossed
并成为阶下囚
And taken prisoner.
罗德尼  这次不会发生这样的事了
That will not happen this time, rodney.
记得吗  我们是受邀请的
We were invited, remember?
这有区别吗
And that makes a difference?
按计划出发
Right on cue.
这倒是似曾相识
This looks a little familiar.
放下武器
Lower your weapons.
很抱歉
My apologies.
请你们谅解
You understand.
小心驶得万年船
You can't be too careful.
欢迎来到我的飞船
Welcome to my ship.
这位是我副官
This is my second-in-command.
我请他来一起参与这次商讨
I've asked him to be a part of these discussions.
请坐
Please, sit.
有果盘  不错啊
Fruit bowl, nice touch.
我们在旅途中准备的
Well, we picked them up on our travels.
我想有水果相伴会令我们的商讨
I thought it would make our discussions
更加愉悦和谐
More comfortable.
希望这些水果和种它们的农民一样美味
I hope they prove as delicious as the farmers who grew them.
我们还是直奔主题吧
All right, let's just get this over with.
我获知你们有个建议
So, I understand you have a proposal,
说是重大突破之类的
A breakthrough of some kind?
这是凯勒医生
This is dr. keller.
他们我们的首席医疗官
She's our chief medical officer,
她将把一切解释给你听
And she's going to explain everything to you.
正如你所知
Uh, as you may already know,
近期我们无意中发现了
We recently stumbled across a lab
迈克尔的实验室
Belonging to michael,
就是那个幽灵...
The wraith that we--
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
当然
Of course you do.
你们成功战胜他的消息
Word of your success against him
已经在我们当中迅速传开了
Spread rapidly among my kind.
非常感激
We are very grateful.
相信我  我们可不是为你们而消灭他的
Trust me, we didn't do it for you.
不管怎样  我们恢复了他实验室的数据库
Anyway, we recovered a database from his lab
这让我们可以继续他的研究...
That allowed us to continue his research into--
你们有什么目的?
For what purpose?
我已经试验出一种基因疗法
We've come up with a gene therapy
可以改变幽灵的基因
That alters wraith dna
虽然只是一小部分  但意义非凡
In a small but significant way.
简而言之
In a nutshell--
我们能够成功治疗
We think we can make it so that you,
你以及任何一个幽灵
And any other wraith we treat,
你们从此不需要在以人类为食
Will never need to feed on humans again.
真是荒谬
This is absurd.
事实上  这不是什么大不了的
Well, actually, it's not as big of a change
你可以想的到
As you might think.
你们身体的各个器官已经具备
Your bodies already contain all the organs necessary
消化食物的能力
To digest food.
接着
Here.
试试这个
Try this.
如果我吃了这水果
If I consume this,
它能给我带来短暂的愉悦感
It may give me a moment's pleasure,
但不能长时间满足我的需求
But it will not sustain me.
但这是可以改变的
But that can change,
至少理论上行得通
At least in theory.
为什么我们要这样做
Why would we want this?
换句话说对我们有什么好处
Of what benefit is it?
考虑一下吧
Well, think about it.
如果你们以这些为食物
If you put yourself on regular food,
就能放弃无尽的抢劫和屠戮
You could give up all those tiresome cullings.
这样你们就会比其他的幽灵
It would give you a significant advantage
更具优势
Over other hives.
更不用说从理论上
Not to mention I could stop waiting
我们还想找机会杀光你们呢
for the chance to kill you, in theory.
我们进食能给予我们力量
Our current feeding process gives us strength,
自愈和长寿的能力
Our ability to heal, our longevity.
我们还不能完全肯定
Well, um, we're not entirely sure
这样的改变是否会影响你们的...  天赋
How this change would affect your, um... gifts.
这些能力可能会保留
They may continue,
但也有可能就此减弱
Although possibly in a diminished form.
有可能失去?
Possibly?
这些难以在实验室测试中取得答案
It's difficult to know from lab tests.
只有做过活体临床试验
We can't be sure
才能最终确定结果
Until we administer it to, um, live subjects.
别忘了迈克尔把改良过的赫方药物
Well, let's not forget that michael spread the modified
散播到几十个星球  可能还不止
hoffan drug to dozens of worlds, possibly more.
又有谁能清楚知道具体在哪呢
I mean, no one knows for sure, right?
这意味着你们每次进食
Which means that every time you feed,
都是冒着风险的
You're taking a risk.
目前最基本的是  周围已经没有足够的食物了
Bottom line is, there's not enough food to go around.
这就导致你们幽灵族互相残杀
That's why you wraith are at each other's throats.
所以说
So...
你们的机会来了
Here's your chance.
这样是不对的
This is wrong.
我们不应该来这的
We shouldn't be here.
不知道  不过好像
I don't know, from where I was sitting,
事情谈的还挺顺利
Things seemed to go pretty well.
是啊
Yeah.
你看起来对这事不太乐观
You don't seem too happy about it.
我本希望他们会有点抵制
I was just expecting a little more resistance.
他还没同意呢
Well, he hasn't said yes yet.
话是没错  但直觉告诉我他会同意的
Yeah, but something makes me think he wants to.
为什么不同意呢  这是个很合理的建议
And why not? it is a reasonable offer.
我们为什么要选择治疗他们这条路呢
Why are we thinking of ways to fix them
还不如直接消灭他们
When we should be thinking of ways to kill them?
我们已经用了4年暴力手段
We've been trying to do that for four years.
他们依然健在
They're still here.
幽灵族不值得我们同情
The wraith may not deserve our consideration,
但正如约翰所说  我们这么做不是为了他们
But as john pointed out, we're not doing this for them.
这里总有点什么不对劲
There's something going on here,
他有事瞒着我们
Something he's not telling us.
真令人惊讶
What a surprise.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
打扰到各位了?
Am I disturbing you?
欢迎
Come in.
我已考虑过你们的建议
I have... considered your offer.
还真是神速啊
That was fast.
我很赞同你们的想法
I believe your idea has merit,
如果你们的治疗能够成功
If you can make the treatment to work.
会成功的
It'll work.
当然
Of course,
仅仅改变一艘蜂巢战舰的幽灵意义不大
Converting a single hive would be pointless.
并不会给这星系的人类带来实质性的改变
It would make little difference to the humans of this galaxy
反而使我们成为幽灵中的异类
And would make us pariahs amongst are own kind.
等等
Wait a minute,
你不是和其他幽灵结成同盟了吗
I thought you worked with a whole group of hives.
是的  但我可能夸大了我在
I do, but I may have... exaggerated my position
同盟军中的地位
Within the alliance.
他是人微言轻啊
He doesn't have the clout.
那么他对我们就没用了
Then he's no good to us.
你们只需要说服一个人就可以
There's only one you need to convince.
在同盟军的所有女王中
Among all the queens in the alliance,
有一位最具权势的女王
One sits above the rest.
我们叫她第一女王
We call her the primary.
那个无敌女王?
The uber-queen?
只要说服她  天下幽灵都会服从
Convince her, and the rest will fall into line.
那就去说服她啊
Then convince her.
第一女王只和其他女王联系
She will only speak with another queen.
而你们女王去年在
And your queen was killed last year
亚特兰蒂斯上空被死了
In the skies above atlantis.
很遗憾  是的
Regrettably, yes,
但是第一女王不知道此事
But the primary does not know this.
你...
You...
你蒙混进同盟军
You bluffed your way into the alliance
然后骗他们说你们还有女王?
And convinced them you still have a queen?
否则他们是不会接纳我们的
They would not have accepted me otherwise.
直到现在
Up to now,
我还可以一直暗度陈仓
I've been able to maintain this subterfuge,
不过面对面的交流就比较棘手了
But a face-to-face meeting, that would be difficult.
事实上  只有一个人能帮助我
In fact, there is only one person who could help me.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
相信我  我也是深思熟虑后做的决定
Believe me, this is not a decision I am taking lightly.
你有意识到他叫你做的事有多危险吗
Do you realize what he's asking you to do?
凯勒医生向我保证
Well, dr. keller assures me
幽灵化是完全可以逆转的
That the procedure is completely reversible
而且没有持续的后遗症
And will have no lasting ill-effects.
我不是说幽灵化
I'm not talking about the procedure.
我知道
I know.
听我说  即使这能成功
Look, even if this works,
即使幽灵们能停止进食
Even if all the wraith stop feeding,
你认为他们能一夜之间就变成谦谦君子
You think they're going to become nice and friendly overnight?
不会
No.
他们会拥有强大的技术优势
They're going to have a massive technological advantage.
你言下之意是他们会奴役
You're suggesting they will enslave
这星系的人类取代以他们为食
the people of this galaxy rather than feed on them.
我们星系就曾经发生过这一切
We've seen the same thing happen in our galaxy.
你怎么不早点提出反对意见
You didn't voice this objection before.
那时没人让你去冒生命危险
Nobody was asking you to risk your life.
我的幽灵基因使我成为唯一合适的人
My wraith DNA makes me the only possible candidate.
换作别人的话会马上被女王发现
Anyone else would be detected by the queen.Immediately.
好吧  如果这样  我的问题是
Well, that's fine, by my question is,
为什么非得现在
Why now?
幽灵族正在互相残杀
The wraith are busy killing each other.
为什么我们不能坐享其成呢
Why don't we just sit back and watch?
最后肯定会有一方胜利
Eventually, one faction will emerge victorious,
然后一切又将恢复原样了
And then everything will go back to the way it was.
但不是这会儿
But maybe not for a while,
我们等的起啊
So we can afford to wait.
如果托德联盟被毁灭
And if todd's alliance is destroyed?
我们就再也没有
We may never have
如此好的机会了
Another opportunity like this again.
我也承认  用这个方法解决幽灵族的问题
I admit, this may not solve the wraith problem
并非一劳永逸
Once and for all,
但在不久的将来总会有活生生的人
But there are people alive today
被挑选出来干这个
Who will be culled in the coming weeks and months,
只要我能救他们  即使是少数
And if I can save even some of them,
我也得试试
I have to try.
即使不是为我自己  为我儿子也值得
If not for myself, then for my son.
谢帕德中校  请回话
Colonel sheppard, come in.
这是谢帕德  说吧
This is sheppard, go ahead.
伍尔希先生通知你
Mr. woolsey wanted me to inform you, sir,
他到了
He's here.
你确定你准备好了吗
You sure you're ready for this?
我已时刻准备着
As ready as I'll ever be.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry. i...
我觉得你是因为我的研究
I feel like you're being pressured into this
才被迫参与进来的
Because of my research.
我没有被迫参与
I am not being pressured into anything,
你的研究拯救了千百人
And your research may save thousands,
甚至上万人的生命
Even millions of lives.
记住了
Remember that.
好吧
Right.
有什么需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
给我记住了
Just remember,
她要是出了什么事儿
If anything happens to her,
你就算逃到天涯海角
There won't be anywhere in the galaxy
我也把你抓出来
You can hide.
说完了吗
Is that all?
好吧
Right.
病人怎么样了
How is my patient?
状况良好
She's fine.
很好  那我们开始吧
Very well, let's get started.
别担心
Don't worry,
他只是技术顾问
He's just here as a technical advisor.
手术由我主刀
I'm going to be performing the surgery.
好了  我们开始吧
All right, we're ready.
我们什么时候才能去看她
When are we going to get to see her?
总要花点时间的  放松一下
Give it some time, just relax.
我放松不了  我喝了差不多有三杯咖啡
I can't. I had, like, three cups of coffee.
我实在太亢奋了
I'm completely wired.
真的么  我怎么没注意到
Really? I hadn't noticed.
好了  现在你们可以见她了
All right, you can see her now.
我看起来怎样
How do I look?
你想让我们俩都死于非命吗
Are you trying to get us both killed?
我不懂
I do not understand.
只要稍稍露出破绽
At the first sign of deception,
女王就会毫不犹豫的撕破我们的喉咙
The primary will not hesitate to slit our throats!
你说过她能感觉到我的幽灵基因的
You said she would sense my wraith dna.
我担心的不是你的基因
It is not your dna that concerns me.
而是你的行为
It is your manner,
举止
Your bearing.
你表现出来的担忧
You project apprehension.
在这种情况下
Well, given the circumstances--
这也许是可以理解的
It may be understandable,
但绝对无法接受
But it is not acceptable!
总之
Above all,
你绝对不能表现得太软弱
You must never show weakness.
现在...
Now...
再来一次!
Again!
这得花多少时间
How long is this going to take, anyway?
直到她的女王
Until todd's satisfied
令托德满意为止
She can pass as a wraith queen.
就我个人而言
You know, personally,
我不太赞成莽撞行事
I'm not inclined to rush this thing.
我觉得她表现得很不错
She's already too convincing if you ask me.
已经有点吓到我了
Creeps me out.
她仍然是泰勒  即使现在面目狰狞
She's still teyla, underneath all that.
也许这就是问题所在
Maybe that's the problem.
听着  对这事儿我没你们那么紧张
Look, I'm not any crazier about this than you guys,
事实上
But the fact is,
托德也是命悬一线
Todd's putting his life on the line, too.
如果他不认为她能蒙混过关
I don't think he'd go in there with her
肯定不会随同前往的
If he didn't think she could pull this off.
泰勒在哪儿
Where's teyla?
休息
Resting.
很高兴告诉你们
You'll be pleased to know
我们已经从蜂巢级母舰处得到回应
We've received word back from the primary's hive.
他们通知我们前往会面
We've been instructed to meet them at their current location.
那  有什么计划
So, what's the plan?
我们一抵达
Once we arrive,
就与舰队取得联系并直接前往
We make contact with the ship and make our way over.
然后泰勒提出我的建议
Then teyla will put forward my proposal.
你的建议?
Oh, your proposal?
相信我  我们最好不要让女王
Believe me, the less the primary knows
知道我们之间的交易
About my dealings with the humans of atlantis,
如果她不知道是我们提出来的
If she doesn't know it's coming from us,
她怎么和我们合作呢
What are the chances she's going to buy it?
我们联盟最近也
Our alliance has recently been dealt
倍受打击
A number of setbacks.
你们也会被人砍啊
You're getting your asses kicked.
的确
Indeed.
虽然女王永远不会承认
Although the primary would never admit it out loud,
但有一点可以肯定  她求生的本能
But the one thing stronger than her pride
比她的自尊
Is her instinct
更为强大
For survival.
别紧张
Don't be nervous.
我不紧张
I am not.
那么...
So...
我们终于见面了
At long last we meet.
的确
Indeed.
我的许多手下开始认为
Many among my crew were beginning to think
你并不存在
You didn't exist.
你应该让他们站出来与我对峙
You must point them out to me,
那样我好消除他们的疑虑
So that I may remove all doubt from their minds.
没必要了
That will no longer be necessary.
到我船上来
Make your way to my ship,
别再让我干等了
And do not keep me waiting again.
她欣赏你
She likes you.
你这么认为?
You think so?
态度温和的比想象中要好多了
It was as warm a reception as we could expect.
进展如何
How'd it go?
显然  十分顺利
Apparently, quite well.
他们预备了飞船
They're preparing a shuttle
准备带我过去见她
To take me over to the other hive.
你随时可以终止这一切的
You know we can pull the plug anytime you want,
只要你开口说
You just give us the word.
不
No.
已经走到这一步了
We've come this far.
我就要坚持到底
I intend to go through with this.
好吧  我们在这儿等着
Well, we'll be right here.
一旦出什么差错  就立刻把你弄出去
If anything goes wrong, we'll get you out.
不会出差错的
But nothing's going to.
是啊  当然不会了  我只是说  假如
Well, no, of course not, but I'm just saying, if it does--
罗德尼...
Rodney...
当然不会出错
Which it won't.
在那儿千万小心
Just be careful over there.
欢迎来到我的飞船
Welcome to my ship.
你们的女王在哪儿
Where is your queen?
她马上就到
You will meet her in time.
通知舰桥他们上来了
Inform the bridge they're onboard.
进行超空间飞行
Take us to hyperspace.
这不在协议范畴之内
This was not part of the agreement.
也没有说在这里进行会面
You did not expect us to conduct this meeting here,
在你的舰队武器射程之内?
Within weapons range of your hive?
怎么说我们也是同一联盟的
We are part of the same alliance.
除非你不信任我们
Unless you do not trust us?
我从不相信陌生人
I make it a practice to trust no one I do not know.
正好女王也这么想
It is how the queen wishes it.
跟我来
Follow me.
这边请
Please.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
第一女王的蜂巢母舰飞入了超空间
The primary's hive just went into hyperspace.
什么
What?
这不属于协议的范畴啊
That wasn't part of the deal.
的确不是
No, it was not.
那他们去哪儿
Where'd they go?
我也不知道
I do not know.
压根儿没法追踪他们
There is no way to track them.
他在撒谎
he's lying.
若楠?
Uh, ronon?
我发誓  我对此一无所知
I assure you, I know nothing of this.
若楠...
Ronon...
看来我们除了相互信任别无他法
It appears we have no choice but to trust each other.
你马上就能见到女王
The queen shall see you shortly.
你搞什么鬼
What have you done?
我发誓我也没料到会这样
I swear I did not expect this to happen.
我们没有危险
We're in no danger.
如果女王不信任我们  我们已经挂了
If the queen did not believe us, we'd be dead already.
那如果她开始怀疑了呢
And if she begins to suspect?
我们被困在飞船上了
We are trapped on this ship.
没事的
Everything will be fine,
只要你好好演你的角色
Provided you continue to play your part.
我们得按计划行事
We must proceed as planned.
他在这干嘛
What is he doing here?
有他在场多少有点用
I thought his presence would be useful,
至少一直以来是他跟你打交道
As he is the one you've been dealing with up until now.
我讨厌意外
I do not like surprises.
我也是
Nor do i,
而我们一上船
And yet you are the one
你却突然将飞船
Who took your ship to hyperspace
开到超空间里去
The moment we stepped aboard.
你若是处在我的位置
If you were in my position,
就会知道安全第一的重要性
You might understand the need for such precautions.
很好
Very well.
跟我来
Come.
坐下谈
Let's sit.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
这是什么意思
What is the meaning of this?
原谅我
Forgive me,
但事情就得这样
But this is the way it must be.
你得说是你杀了她
You must say that you killed her.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
这就是我们族的规矩
This is how it is done with our kind.
这就是我们族的权力传递法则
This is how power changes hands.
但我不想
But I do not want--
听我说!
Listen to me!
这些人肯定会有所不快
The crew will not be happy,
但他们更不愿意没有女王
But nor will they wish to be without a queen.
是你趁她不备
You caught her off-guard.
许多人会认为
Many will perceive that to mean
她正在变弱
That she was growing weak.
你只需要
All you need to do
说服他们你是个有能力的代替者
Is convince them that you are a capable replacement,
他们就会接受你的
And they will accept you.
要是我不行呢?
And if I can't?
那我俩都得挂掉
Then we're both dead.
这是怎么回事
What is this?
这是我应得的
I have taken what is rightfully mine.
你杀了她!
You killed her!
是的
Yes,
你最好接受这一点
And you are the better for it.
杀人就要偿命
You will die for this.
你怎么敢用抢指着你们的女王!
How dare you point a weapon at your queen!
她才是我们的女王
This was my queen!
已经不再是了
Not anymore.
她的力量日渐减弱
She was growing weak.
她再也不能完全掌控联盟
She no longer had full control over the alliance.
如果你还懵然不知
If you can't see that,
实属愚昧
You're a fool.
我允许你说话了吗
Did I ask you to speak for me?
回女王陛下  没有
No, my queen.
下次若再多口舌
Wag your tongue like that again,
你这条舌头就不用要了
And I will remove it.
清楚了吗
Is that understood?
清楚了  女王陛下
Yes, my queen!
马上离开超空间  全面检查飞船状态
Now, drop us out of hyperspace and run a full diagnostic.
我要掌握我新旗舰的最新情况
I wish to know the state of my new flagship.
然后把这个...东西处理掉
And have this... thing removed from my sight.
是的  女王陛下
Yes, my queen.
我查问了这里的人员
I have surveyed the crew.
所幸的是  他们成功被我们骗了
You'll be pleased to know they were entirely fooled.
你葫芦里究竟卖什么药
What were you thinking?
你把你我两人的性命至于极度危险之中
You put both our lives at terrible risk.
我知道
I know.
请容我解释一下
If you'll allow me to explain--
你怎么可以这样做
How could you do this?
这是必须的
It was necessary.
前女王是不会同意你的提议的
The former queen was never going to accept your proposal.
所以你索性杀掉她  让我成为替罪羔羊?
And so you killed her and forced me to take the blame?
若是我来承担  我会被赐予死罪
If I had taken the blame, I would have been killed,
而你也会成为阶下囚
And you would have been held captive.
这恐怕与我们初衷不一致
That was not the desired outcome.
你要明白
You must understand,
我们的文化截然不同
Our culture is different from your own.
到什么山就要唱什么歌
We govern ourselves by different rules.
你声称自己干掉了女王
It was important for you to claim ownership
才是当务之急
Of the act of killing the queen.
你早该把这种谋朝夺位的做法
You should have informed me of your intention
跟我说清楚
To make me queen of this hive.
或许吧
Perhaps,
若你事先知晓  我恐怕你未必会
But I doubt you would have gone through with it
同意这样做
Had you known.
正是
You're right.
这是个荒唐轻率的计划
It was a foolish, reckless plan.
多数幽灵人渴望被统治
Most wraith seek to be ruled.
他们最害怕群龙无首
They fear being without a queen.
我深知  假若你可以证明自己
I knew that if you presented yourself
胜任女王之位
As a viable substitute,
他们多数也归顺于你的
Most of them would just fall in line.
多数人?
Most of them?
重点是  我们已经顺利完成计划
The point is, we have achieved what we set out to do.
你已经成功地
You are now effectively
取得联盟的控制权
In control of the alliance.
我们可以畅通无阻的执行
We may now implement dr. keller's plan
凯勒医生的计划
Without hindrance.
在这之后  我们就没必要继续表演了
Then there is no further need for us to continue this charade.
先带我回你的飞船去
Take me back to your ship.
马上  但首先
Soon, but first,
你要再稍等片刻
You must allow some time
树立起自己的威严
For order to be restored,
让所有事情重回正轨
For things to return to normal.
然后  你才能离开
Once they do, you may take your leave,
让他们自我良性循环
And no one on this crew will be the wiser.
我还是觉得这是个陷阱
I still say this was a setup.
我也不知道  肯尼看到飞船消失的时候
I don't know, kenny seemed pretty surprised
似乎也很吃惊
When that ship disappeared.
谁
Who?
肯尼  这里的副指挥官
Kenny, the second-in-command.
我们什么时候开始
Well, since when did we start
这样子称呼他的
Calling him that?
也许他也是被卖的
Maybe he wasn't in on it.
我也说不清  如果托德想劫走泰勒
I don't know, if todd wanted to kidnap teyla,
他早在我们到达的时候就可以下手
He would've done it the second we arrived.
这不合情理
It doesn't add up.
说真的
Seriously,
下次我们要给他们起名字的时候
The next time we have to name one of these guys,
至少也要投票决定吧
We should take a vote.
那我们该怎么做呢
So, what are we going to do?
当然不能坐以待毙
We can't stay here.
这里到处都是幽灵人的守卫
We're stuck on a hive surrounded by wraith.
这对我们很不利
Not exactly our strongest position.
我只有一艘飞船了  你说怎么办
All I've got is a jumper. where do you want to go?
我们找一个星门
Well, we get to a gate,
然后回到亚特兰蒂斯
We gate back to atlantis,
然后想办法救回泰勒
And then we figure out where they took teyla.
具体怎样操作
How, exactly?
我还没想好详细的计划
Okay, so I haven't quite worked out the details yet,
但...
But...
我们收到一些情报了
We have something.
第一女王的旗舰离开了超空间
The primary's hive has dropped out of hyperspace.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
我们正在接收信号
We're receiving a signal.
这是托德的亚空间传送机
It's todd's subspace transmitter.
他们在真空区巨大星云的边界
They're in empty space, on the edge of a large nebula.
他们到那里去干什么
What are they doing out there?
管它的  这是我们的机会
Who cares? this is our chance.
去追踪他们
Let's go after them.
我已绘制出航线
I've already plotted the course,
但要知道  我们冒冒然前去
But you should know that it will arouse suspicion
会引起他们的怀疑
For us to arrive unannounced.
这个晚点再担心好了
Well, let's worry about that later.
现在  最重要的就是让他们收到
For now, this is the closest thing they've got
这个求救信号
To a distress signal.
女王陛下  抱歉打扰了
I'm sorry to disturb you, my queen.
我们收到紧急信号
We've received an urgent report.
你要她自己看吗
You intend to make her read it?
在离这不远处  我们的捕食场之一的
A hive belonging to another alliance
上方  发现了
Has been detected
来自另一个联盟的飞船
Above one of our feeding grounds not far from here.
有尝试过和他们取得联系吗
Have you tried to contact them?
他们并没有回应
They are not responding.
派遣最近的飞船去查明情况
Dispatch the closest hive to investigate.
我们已经是最近的了
We are the closest hive.
要截击只能亲自去了
It falls upon us to intercept.
我们必须留守此地
We must remain here.
陛下
My queen,
或许  我们该私下谈谈
Perhaps we should discuss this in private.
退下
Leave us.
我们必须出击
We must respond to this.
退缩只会被认为是懦弱之举
To do otherwise will read as weakness.
船员们会不理解的
The crew will not understand.
就让他们猜忌去
Then let them be confused.
说的话像个真正的女王
Spoken like a true queen,
做的事却让他们暗生怀疑
But you risk breeding suspicion.
当下  他们信奉你
For the moment, they believe you,
他们臣服于你
And are prepared to serve you,
若作出不合理的决定
But if you break that trust
就会失去威信
By making irrational decisions,
他们就会毫不犹豫地推翻你
They will quickly fall away from you.
你的飞船怎办
What about your ship?
也许他们正赶过来
It is probably already on its way.
只要他们到达  就会接收到
They will pick up on our new location
我们新所在地的信号
As soon as they arrive.
通知舰桥去策划航线
Inform the bridge to set a course.
有一点  肯尼是对的
Now, kenny's right about one thing--
倘若我们二次离开超空间
The second we drop out of hyperspace,
女王旗舰一定会
The primary's hive ship's
发觉形势不对
Going to know something's up.
我们提早离开
We drop out early,
剩下的路程就改用飞船
Go the rest of the way by jumper.
这样太费时了
That's going to take too long.
我们需要分散他们的注意
We need a diversion.
那么...该怎么分散他们的注意力呢
So, what... what kind of a diversion?
你想的和我想的一样吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
是的
Yeah,
但我不认为我们可以依靠
But I don't think we can rely on kenny
肯尼来发号施令
To give the order, though.
我们没有给机会他发挥
We don't give him a choice.
你们说什么呢
What are you talking about?
什么发号施令
What order?
不  不  慢着
Oh, no, wait a minute.
你们不是想要攻击别的飞船吧
You're not thinking about attacking the other ship?
听着  这是唯一让他们分散注意的途径
Look, it's the only way to keep them occupied
给我们充裕的时间登上敌舰
Long enough to get on board,
救出泰勒  再返回
Get teyla, and get back.
但这十分冒险
But it's also incredibly risky.
敌我舰队都有被摧毁的危险
I mean, either of the ships could be destroyed.
我们只要保证
Well, we'll just make sure
在这发生之前把她救出
We get her out of there before that happens.
我知道成功的几率
Look, I realize the odds
实在不高  罗德尼
Aren't exactly in our favor, rodney,
但我们再不采取行动
But the longer we wait to get teyla,
就再也救不出她了
The more likely it is we never will.
我们只有冒险一搏了
We just have to keep all of our options open.
我们已到达捕食场了
We have reached the feeding ground.
他们会尝试提出要谈判
They will attempt to negotiate a concession,
但你必须坚定立场
But you must stand firm.
他们会威胁要攻击
They may even threaten to attack,
但他们也和我们一样
But they will not want to fight
不愿战斗
Any more than we do.
那艘飞船尝试和我们联系
The other hive is trying to contact us.
别管他们  准备攻击
Ignore them. charge weapons.
你要莫名地发动进攻吗
You wish to attack unprovoked?
这并非毫无理由
We were provoked.
他们入侵了我们的领地
They have encroached upon our territory.
我要消灭他们
I want them destroyed.
马上
Now!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
你说呢
What does it look like?
我叫你和他们谈判
I told you to talk to them.
你也叫我不要暴露懦弱的一面
You also told me to show no weakness.
他们还击了
They're returning fire.
我们船体受伤了
We're taking hull damage.
派出小战机
Deploy the darts.
这种情况下
Under these conditions,
他们会损失惨重的
They will suffer heavy losses.
我很清楚这样做的代价
I'm fully aware of the costs,
面对这样的入侵  我们就要坚定立场
But we must take a firm stance against intrusions such as this.
你这样做是有目的的
You're doing this on purpose,
要屠杀幽灵人
To kill wraith.
为数过半的先头部队已被击下
Half the first wave has been destroyed.
幸存的部队已飞近船身
But the survivors are now too close
不再受到火力威胁
To be affected by the ship's weapons,
它们可以随意攻击了
And they can attack at will.
但敌军也会派出小战机
Until the enemy launches their own darts
进行拦截
To intercept.
那也要一段时间之后
That will take time.
幸运的是我们已经来了个攻其不备
With any luck, we've caught them off guard.
他们不在那里
They're not here.
他们究竟在哪里
Where the hell are they?
他们转移了
They've moved,
去了另一个人口更密集的捕食场
To one of our more populated feeding grounds.
为什么
What for?
我怎么知道  我又不在他们那边
I do not know. I'm not on the ship.
如果要我猜的话
But if I had to guess,
我想大概他们去了捕食
I would say they've gone to cull.
现在怎办
What now?
还有选择吗  当然是追击他们
What else can we do? we go after them.
如果他们转移到了超空间
If they jump into hyperspace,
我们不是要失去他们的行踪了吗
We're going to lose them again, right?
确实如此  托德的导航定位器
Pretty much. todd's locator beacon
在超空间会失效
Doesn't work in hyperspace.
我们该停止这你追我赶的游戏
We got to stop playing catch-up.
这星球有星门吗
Is there a stargate on that planet?
当然
Of course.
带我们去那里
Then drop us off.
在那里驾飞船去会快一点
We can get there faster in the jumper.
你打算怎么登上他们的飞船
How do you intend to get on board their ship?
这个不用你操心
Don't worry about it.
只管把我们带到最近的星门就好
Just get us to the nearest stargate.
女王陛下  现在我们的小战机在数量上是以一敌二
My queen, our darts are outnumbered two to one.
如果我们不把他们召回
If we do not recall them now,
他们会被全歼的
They will be wiped out.
当联盟统治银河系时
And their sacrifice will be remembered
他们就会永载史册
When this alliance rules the galaxy.
怎么回事
What was that?
我们失去了中央武器阵列
We just lost the medial weapons array.
继续用其它武器攻击
Keep firing all other batteries.
我们马上就可以看到他们了
All right, we should be coming up on them now.
等等  怎么会有两批人马
Wait a minute, there's two of them.
什么
What?
他们在互相攻击
And they're fighting.
还是以命相搏啊
They're not pulling any punches, either.
继续找信号
Still picking up that signal?
好的
Yeah.
没错  就是那个
All right, it's that one.
形势不妙啊
They're not doing so good.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
他们肯定是失去了大部分武器
They must've lost some of their weapons.
我是说  他们快要弹尽粮绝了
I mean, they're seriously outgunned.
我们是时候挺身而出了
We got to do something.
上周我和泽兰卡谈过
You know, just last week I was talking to zelenka
飞船用的代达罗斯号辐射系统
About trying to reverse-engineer
的能源回溯问题
A  daedalus  beaming system for the jumpers.
然后呢
And?
这个  我们还毫无结果
Oh, well, no, we're nowhere near close.
我想说的是这个阿斯加德技术
I mean, the asgard technology's
复杂到难以想象
Incredibly complicated--
你现在说这个有什么意义
What the hell are you bringing this up for now?
我是指这东西可能
I'm just saying that this would be
非常适合这种状况
The perfect situation for something like...
大家坚持下
all right, everybody hold on.
我们要进去了
We're going in.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我要力挽狂澜
Trying to tip the scales a little.
你疯啦  他们可以看见我们
Are you nuts? they can see us!
这样有用吗
Think that did it?
试过就知道了
We're about to find out.
这完全不可能
That's impossible.
敌舰刚刚爆炸了
The enemy hive just exploded.
干得好  我的女王
Well done, my queen.
也许下一次
Perhaps next time,
你就不应该这么早怀疑我的策略
You will not be so quick to question my tactics.
召回飞船
Recall the darts.
飞船正在返回中
Darts are heading back.
舱门已打开
Bay doors are open.
机会来了
All right, that's our cue.
我要进去
I'm going in.
我们要去哪里?
where do we go?
不知道
I don't know.
你这时什么意思
What do you mean, you don't know?
这个难以言传
It's hard to tell.
很像不在这一层
I think we're on the wrong level.
而且信号四处游荡
Plus, the signal keeps moving around.
至少托德还活着是件好事
That's a good sign todd's alive.
你还没说泰勒到底在哪呢
Still doesn't tell us anything about teyla.
好吧
All right.
我想可能是这
It's this way. I think.
我们要转移一下了
We're going to have to circle back.
太好了  此路又不通
Oh, great, I got to figure this out all over again?
有巡逻队来了
Another patrol coming this way.
现在该怎么办
So, what are we going to do?
只剩华山一条路了
We got no choice.
走吧
Let's move.
哪边
Which way?
我觉得答案在那里
I guess that answers that.
报告女王
Inform the queen.
有人入侵
We have intruders.
怎么办
Now what?
我猜得话
Well, if I had to guess,
我们会被抓到女王面前
I'd say we'll be taken in front of the queen,
严刑拷打获取信息
Who will demand answers
不然就拿我们下饭
And threaten to feed on us.
我只是希望到时
At which time,
可以有点锦囊妙计来金蝉脱壳
I hope to have plan to get us out of here.
你真会让人安心
Very reassuring.
是泰勒  她还活着
It's teyla. she's alive.
罗德尼  小声点
rodney, quiet.
你们先下去
Leave us.
约翰  若楠  罗德尼
John, ronon, rodney,
见到你们实在太好了
It is good to see you,
不过你们不应该来的
But you should not have come for me.
怎么了  发生什么事了
Why? what's going on?
我迟点再解释
I'll explain later,
不过现在千万不要想着逃跑
But you must not attempt to escape.
你们不会有危险的
You're in no danger.
我成了这艘舰的女王
I'm now queen of this hive.
你说什么
Wait, what?
说来话长
It is a long story.
不  我们有飞船在这  随时可以离开啊
No, we got a jumper here, we can leave right now.
不  我要把我的位置巩固下来
No, I must solidify my position first.
这时唯一的机会
It is the only chance we have
可以让联盟成功接受治疗
To ensure the alliance will accept the treatment.
否则所有努力都打水漂了
Otherwise, this will all have been for nothing.
好吧
All right.
咱们只能继续玩下去了
We'll let it play out.
我的女王
My queen...
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
谁允许你来我寝室的
Who authorized you to wait in my quarters?
我不请自到的
I let myself in.
有点事要跟你私下商量
I needed to see you in private.
我现在不想商量什么
I do not wish to speak right now.
晚点再来吧
Come back later.
恐怕我不能服从了
I'm afraid I can't do that.
我是你的女王  我命令你
I am your queen. I command you--
你不是女王
You are not my queen.
你居然敢这样跟我说话
How dare you speak to me like this.
还不赶快给我消失
Remove yourself from my sight immediately.
我看到你和亚特兰帝斯的囚犯在聊天
I saw you talking with the prisoners from atlantis.
那有如何
And?
我不可以审问我舰上的囚犯?
I may not interrogate prisoners on my own ship?
你当然可以
Oh, you may,
不过你叫他们囚犯也太奇怪了吧
Though it is odd that you refer to them
我可是凑巧听到了你们的谈话内容哦
I overheard what you said to them.
你们是互相认识的
You knew them, and they knew you,
我还扪心自问
And I asked myself,
这怎么可能呢
"how is such a thing possible?"
你一上战舰时我就怀疑你了
I suspected you right from the moment you set foot upon my ship,
但那仅仅只是怀疑
And against my better judgment,
我让你登上飞船
I allowed you to remain onboard
你却暗通外敌
While you committed treachery after treachery.
保卫战舰是我的职责
It was my duty to defend the ship,
但我失败了
And I failed.
恐怕你要倒台了  女王陛下
I'm afraid your reign is over, my queen.
他不会再打扰你了
He'll not be bothering you any further.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的母舰几分钟前到了
My hive arrived moments ago.
已经安排好谢帕德中校和
I've arranged for colonel sheppard,
若楠以及麦凯博士
Ronon, and dr. mckay
的快速转移了
To be transferred there immediately.
太好了
Good.
我什么时候可以离开啊
When do I join them?
等一切完结以后
As soon as this is all over.
另外  我也要离开一阵
...and thus, I will be taking my leave of you,
回到母舰上
And returning to my former hive.
我会留下我所信任的指挥官
I am leaving behind my trusted commander.
让我再说清楚点
Let me be clear,
你们仍将被列入保护对象
You will still fall under my protection,
不过当我不在时
But in my absence,
你们要像服从我一样服从他的命令
You will heed his every order as if it were my own.
他说的话
When he speaks,
就代表我说的话
It is as though I am speaking through him.
明白了吗
Is that understood?
尊命  女王
Yes, my queen.
好
Good.
是时候了
Then it is time.
护送我去运输船吧
Escort me to my transport.
女王起驾
The queen departs.
干得好
Well done.
我相信你已经排除一切怀疑了
I believe you've managed to allay
你要记住我们这么做的目的
Just remember why we did this,
是为了让尽可能多的幽灵
To disseminate dr. keller's treatment
愿意接受凯勒医生的治疗
To as many wraith as possible.
当然了
Of course.
但我觉得应该让事情
Although I think it might be wise
先冷静一下比较好
To let matters settle for a time first.
要多久
How much time?
很快
Not long.
你不会打算违背协议吧
You're not planning on going back on our agreement,
不  不会的
No, no.
我是说你新官上任就进行
I'm just saying that to press such a radical agenda
这么激进的计划会不会....
So soon after the change in leadership...
没错  可能会有不和谐的声音
Well, it may invite unwelcome questions.
好的
Fine.
很好
Very well--
不过你要牢记
But bear in mind
在这艘船上
That as far as this crew is concerned,
我还是女王
I am still their queen.
当然
Oh, yes.
我会一直关注你的表现
I will be watching you,
一旦发现你有什么越轨行为
And should you step out of line,
我会毫不犹豫的把你革除
I will not hesitate to make a reappearance
很好
Very well.
永久性除掉
Permanently.
你怎么把她变成这样了  医生
What have you done to her, doc?
很搞笑
Very funny.
你感觉怎样
How you feeling?
好多了
Better.
还有点酸痛
Still some soreness,
不过大体已经没事了
But for the most part, it's gone.
很好
Good.
好的  我四处走走
Well, I have rounds,
晚点再回来看你
But I'll come and check on you later.
别让他太为难你噢
Make sure he doesn't give you a hard time.
你确定你没事吧
Sure you're feeling okay?
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
没有什么残留的本能吧
No lingering desires to feed on anything?
只想吃固体食物
Only on solid food.
凯勒医生配的混合剂
The blended concoctions given to me by dr. keller
好像效果一般
Are not very satisfying.
才有2周而已
Well, it's only been two weeks.
再耐心等等吧
Give it some time.
听着
Look, um...
我还没有机会告诉你
I haven't had the chance to tell you
你所做的一切....
That what you did, uh, took...
这个  需要一点勇气
You know, a lot of guts.
我很高兴最终有个完美的结局
I'm just glad it worked out for the best.
托德那儿还有什么新消息吗
Has there been any further word from todd?
还没
Not really.
过几周我们还会有一次会面
We're supposed to meet with him in a few weeks
讨论基因治疗计划
About this whole gene therapy thing.
听说他完全巩固了
Word has it
自己在联盟的领导地位
He's solidified his position as, uh,"leader" of the alliance.
什么
What?
你对托德成功控制整个联盟
Do you not find it strange.That as a result of all of this,
感到很意外吧
Todd now personally has control of that entire alliance?
你觉得这是他一直预谋的
You think that was his plan all along, huh?
这个我考虑过
The thought had crossed my mind.
是啊
Yeah.
不管怎样
Regardless,
形势总算有点好转吧
I think we're better off than we were before.
是的
Yes.
我很赞同你
I suppose you're right.
休息下吧
Get some rest.
我等会回来看你
I'll come back and check on you.